Anna E. Dickinson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Anna E. Dickinson Papers 1859-1951 (bulk 1859-1911)
MSS18424
Dickinson, Anna E. (Anna Elizabeth), 1842-1932
10,000 items
29 containers plus 2 oversize
12.4 linear feet
25 microfilm reels
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Lecturer, reformer, actress, and author. Correspondence, speeches, writings, plays, legal files, financial papers, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, and printed material relating to Dickinson's activities on behalf of abolition and women's rights and suffrage and to her career in the theater.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Allison, William B. (William Boyd), 1829-1908--Correspondence.; Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906--Correspondence.; Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887--Correspondence.; Bowles, Samuel, 1826-1878--Correspondence.; Brooks, Noah, 1830-1903--Correspondence.; Butler, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1818-1893--Correspondence.; Chester, Giraud, 1922- Embattled maiden; the life of Anna Dickinson. 1951.; Davenport, Fanny, 1850-1898--Correspondence.; Dickinson family--Correspondence.; Dickinson, Anna E. (Anna Elizabeth), 1842-1932.; Dickinson, Mary--Correspondence.; Dickinson, Susan--Correspondence.; Douglass, Frederick, 1818-1895--Correspondence.; Everett, Ellen--Correspondence.; Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879--Correspondence.; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872.; Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911--Correspondence.; Hooker, Isabella Beecher, 1822-1907--Correspondence.; Phillips, Wendell, 1811-1884--Correspondence.; Pomeroy, S. C. (Samuel Clarke), 1816-1891--Correspondence.; Reid, Whitelaw, 1837-1912--Correspondence.; Schurz, Carl, 1829-1906--Correspondence.; Tilton, Theodore, 1835-1907--Correspondence.; Twain, Mark, 1835-1910--Correspondence.; Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900--Correspondence.; Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892--Correspondence.
Organizations
Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); State Hospital for the Insane (Danville, Pa.)
Subjects
Antislavery movements--United States.; Education--United States.; Elections--United States--1872.; Elections--United States--1888.; Mentally ill--Commitment and detention--United States.; Presidents--United States--Election--1872.; Presidents--United States--Election--1888.; Psychiatric hospitals--Pennsylvania--Danville.; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877); Slavery--United States.; Theater--United States.; Women's rights--United States.; Women--Suffrage--United States.
Places
United States--Description and travel.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
Titles
Anna E. Dickinson Papers at the Library of Congress
Occupations
Actresses.; Authors.; Lecturers.; Reformers.
Provenance
The papers of Anna E. Dickinson, lecturer, reformer, actress, and author, were given to the Library of Congress in 1933 by Dickinson's estate. Additions to the papers were given in 1955 by Giraud Chester and by an unidentified donor, 1955-1958. A gift from James Harvey Young was received in 1984 and 2004.
Transfers
Some photographic prints and negatives have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division of the Library of Congress where they are identified as part of these papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Anna E. Dickinson are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Microfilm
A microfilm edition of part of these papers is available on twenty-five reels. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division concerning availability for purchase or interlibrary loan. To promote preservation of the originals, researchers are required to consult the microfilm edition as available.
Online Content
The Anna E. Dickinson Papers are available on the Library of Congress Web site at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/collmss.ms000081.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1842, Oct. 28 Born, Philadelphia, Pa.
1859 1860 Taught school
1861 Delivered her first full-length lecture, Concert Hall, Philadelphia, Pa.. Employee, United States Mint, Philadelphia, Pa.
1862 Spoke in New England at invitation of William Lloyd Garrison
1863 Campaigned for the Republican Party in Middle Atlantic states and New England
1865 1875 National lyceum movement lecturer
1868 Published What Answer? (Boston: Ticknor and Fields. 301pp.)
1869 Traveled to California on the transcontinental railroad
1872 Campaigned for Horace Greeley for president
1876 Debut at New Globe Theatre, Boston, Mass.
1879 Published A Ragged Register of People, Places and Opinions (New York: Harper & Brothers. 286pp.)
1888 Campaigned for the Republican Party in the Midwest
1891 Committed to State Hospital for the Insane, Danville, Pa.
1895 1901 Waged libel suits against authorities responsible for her commitment to a hospital for the insane
1895 1932 Lived with George and Sallie Ackley, Goshen, N.Y.
1932, Oct. 22 Died, Goshen, N.Y.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Anna Elizabeth Dickinson (1842-1932) span the period 1859-1951, but are chiefly concentrated in the years 1859-1911. The collection consists of Family Correspondence, General Correspondence, Speeches and Writings File, Legal File, and a Miscellany series including financial papers, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, and research notes of Giraud Chester, Dickinson's biographer. There are also a small Addition and an Oversize series.
Anna Dickinson's papers treat all aspects of her life and include correspondence with the men and women of her circle throughout the country. Although Dickinson did not make copies of most of her letters, she obtained many of the letters she wrote while on national lecture tours to Mary Dickinson, her mother, and Susan Dickinson, her journalist sister. The correspondence described her travel itineraries, her impressions, and her joys and misgivings. They show the reactions of a person whose plays and performances, including A Crown of Thorns and The Test of Honor, were not well received. By 1900 she was estranged from her sister Susan, formerly her closest friend and housemate, and had outlived most of her associates. As recorded in the legal file and in her scrapbooks, she intiated several lawsuits between 1895 and 1901 as a result of her confinement at the State Hospital for the Insane in Danville, Pennsylvania. Other topics include the elections of 1872 and 1888, the Republican Party, psychiatric hospital and her confinement to the State Hospital for the Insane, the Civil War and Reconstruction, and education.
The Speeches and Writings File, contains several of Dickinson's earliest speeches and stage manuscripts. Those not present are often documented by newspaper clippings and scrapbooks. A notebook in the Legal File records her experiences at the State Hospital for the Insane. Only obituaries and a few financial papers relate to her final two decades.
Correspondents include William B. Allison, Susan B. Anthony, Samuel Bowles, Noah Brooks, Benjamin F. Butler, Fanny Davenport, Frederick Douglass, Ellen Everett, Thomas Wentworth Higginson, Isabella Beecher Hooker, Wendell Phillips, Samuel C. Pomeroy, Whitelaw Reid, Carl Schurz, Theodore Tilton, Mark Twain, Charles Dudley Warner, and John Greenleaf Whittier.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in seven series:
Family Correspondence, 1860-1904
General Correspondence, 1859-1911
Speeches and Writings File, 1868-1907
Legal File, 1881-1898
Miscellany, 1863-1951
Addition, 1862-1933
Oversize, 1863-1877
Container List
Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 17, 984
- Family Correspondence, 1860-1904 (Box 1-4, Reel 1-5)
  Letters sent by Anna Dickinson and received from her mother, sister, brother, and other family members.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1860-1862 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - 1863, Jan. 8-Aug. 20
  - 1863, Oct. 1-Dec. 22
  - 1864, Feb. 4-Oct. 22
  - 1865, Feb. 6-1866, Apr. 16
  - 1866, May 9-Dec. 15
  - 1867, Jan. 1-Mar. 30
  - 1867, Apr. 1-July 31
  - 1867, Aug. 1-29
  - 1867. Sept. 2-Dec. 31
  - 1868, Jan. 2-Feb. 25
  - 1868, Mar. 1-31
  - 1868, Apr. 21-Dec. 15
  - 1869, Jan. 24-May 10
  - 1869, June 8-July 24
  - 1869, Aug. 5-Sept. 29
  - 1869, Oct. 28-1870, Feb. 22
  - 1870, Mar. 1-Dec. 6
  - 1871, Jan. 5-Feb. 28 (Box 2, Reel 2)
  - 1871, Mar. 5-Apr. 17
  - 1871, May 1-June 30
  - 1871, July 24-Nov. 27
  - 1871, Dec. 3-1872, Jan. 26
  - 1872, Feb. 15-Mar. 30
  - 1872, Apr. 1-June 25
  - 1872, July 2-31
  - 1872, Aug. 3-30
  - 1872, Sept. 2-Oct. 10
  - 1872, Nov. 8-30
  - 1872, Dec. 2-19
  - 1873, Jan. 3-31
  - 1873, Feb. 2-Mar. 5
  - 1873, Mar. 6-29
  - 1873, Apr. 4-29
  - 1873, May 2-July 31
  - 1873, Aug. 2-28
  - 1873, Sept. 4-28 (Box 3, Reel 3)
  - 1873, Oct. 12-Nov. 30
  - 1873, Dec. 7-1874, Feb. 27
  - 1874, Mar. 8-July 19
  - 1874, Aug. 2-31
  - 1874, Sept. 1-Dec. 30
  - 1875, Jan. 9-Apr. 30
  - 1875, May 3-June 21
  - 1875, July 7-30
  - 1875, Aug. 5-Dec. 8
  - 1876
  - 1877, Apr. 12-Oct. 8
  - 1878, Nov. 5-1879, Feb. 25 (Box 3, Reel 4)
  - 1879, Mar. 11-July 31
  - 1879, Aug. 2-29
  - 1879, Sept. 3-26
  - 1879, Oct. 1-31
  - 1879, Nov. 1-Dec. 29
  - 1880, Jan. 4-Feb. 29
  - 1880, Mar. 2-31
  - 1880, Apr. 1-28
  - 1880, May 2-25
  - 1880, June 1-Oct. 25
  - 1881, Jan. 3-Dec. 25 (Box 4, Reel 4)
  - 1882, Sept. 6-Dec. 25
  - 1883, Jan. 4-July 27
  - 1883, Sept. 18-Dec. 27
  - 1884, Jan. 1-17
  - 1884, Jan. 18-27
  - 1884, Feb. 1-Mar. 15
  - 1884, Mar. 16-31 (Box 4, Reel 5)
  - 1884, Apr. 1-30
  - 1884, May 2-Aug. 15
  - 1885, Mar. 28-June 26
  - 1885, July 6-Aug. 30
  - 1885, Sept. 16-30
  - 1885, Oct. 1-16
  - 1885, Oct. 19-30
  - 1885, Nov. 1-15
  - 1885, Nov. 16-30
  - 1885, Dec. 1-1886, Dec.
  - 1887, Feb. 1-July 24
  - 1888, Sept. 1-15
  - 1888, Sept. 18-30
  - 1888, Oct. 1-31
  - 1888, Nov. 1-1894, June 15
  - Undated
- General Correspondence, 1859-1911 (Box 5-14, Reel 6-17)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent by Dickinson, including postcards, calling card messages, telegrams, and enclosed material.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent and chronologically thereunder. Anonymous, incomplete, fragmentary, initialed, and unitelligible or unidentified correspondence is filed at the end of the series.
  - Ackley, Sallie J., and family, 1892-1910, undated (Box 5, Reel 6)
  - Allen, Elizabeth A., 1877-1878, undated
  - Allison, William B., 1869-1908, undated
  - Allyn, J. P., 1863
  - Ames, Fanny B., 1863, undated
  - Anthony, Susan B., 1864-1895, undated
  - Austin, R. N. and Sallie, 1865-1871
  - Austin, S. F., 1865-1875, undated
  - "A" miscellaneous, 1862-1895, undated
  - Baker, John, 1867
  - Beecher, Henry Ward, 1871-1874, undated
  - Benedict, Frank Lee, 1887-1888
  - Bernard, O. G., 1873-1881 (Box 5, Reel 7)
  - Booth, Marion, 1893-1895, undated
  - Boucicault, Dion, 1877-1879, undated
  - Bowles, Samuel, 1863-1879, undated
  - Brackett, Lou and Walter, 1865-1875, undated
  - Brooks, Noah, 1872-1874, undated
  - Browne, Ele, 1869-1873, undated (Box 6, Reel 7)
  - Bullard, E. P., 1872-1873
  - Bullard, Laura C., 1870-1875, undated
  - Burton, W. J., 1865-1869
  - Butler, Benjamin F., 1866-1892, undated
  - "Ba-Bk" miscellaneous, 1863-1899, undated (Box 5, Reel 8)
  - "Bl-Bn" miscellaneous, 1864-1893, undated (Box 6, Reel 8)
  - "Br-Bz" miscellaneous, 1863-1908, undated
  - Camp, Stephen H., 1868, undated (Box 7, Reel 8)
  - Chase, Lillie B., 1860-1874, undated
  - Clark, Lizzie, 1897-1898, undated
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1871-1874
  - Clarkson, J. S., 1888-1891, undated
  - Clemens, Samuel L., undated
  - Collyer, Robert, 1871-1880, undated
  - Conway, Martin F., 1866-1878, undated
  - Colfax, Schuyler, 1868-1871
  - Croly, Jenny Cunningham, 1877-1888, undated
  - Crowell, Charlotte M., 1866-1891, undated
  - "C" miscellaneous, 1860-1902, undated
  - Douglass, Frederick, 1866-1874
  - Dille, John I., 1888
  - Dupee, Henry D., 1907
  - "D" miscellaneous, 1862-1910, undated (Box 7, Reel 9)
  - Edmunds, Fanny B., undated
  - Evans, Edward P., 1868-1870
  - Everett, Ellen (Box 8, Reel 9)
    - 1866-1896
    - 1897-1910
    - Undated
  - Eytinge, Rose, 1878-1881 (Box 8, Reel 10)
  - "E" miscellaneous, 1862-1893, undated
  - Faithfull, Emily, 1884, undated
  - Ferguson, Julius M., 1892-1899, undated
  - Field, Kate, 1870-1874
  - Fisk, Stephen R., 1877-1880
  - Fitch, R. G., 1877-1880
  - Forney, John W., 1881, undated
  - Fortescue, Jessie, 1894-1899, undated
  - Fortune, Timothy Thomas, 1892-1894
  - Frohman, Daniel, 1871-1893, undated
  - "F" miscellaneous, 1863-1910, undated
  - Gardiner, C.S., 1879-1882
  - Garrison, William Lloyd (1805-1879), and family, 1862-1863
  - Garrison, William Lloyd (1838-1909), Jr., 1906-1907
  - Gillette, William, 1884-1888
  - Gough, John B., 1865-1874, undated
  - Gould, Linus A., 1862-1863
  - Gustafson, Jadel Buddington, 1867-1901
  - "G" miscellaneous, 1861-1897, undated
  - Hanaford, Phoebe A., 1868-1894, undated (Box 9, Reel 10)
  - Habberton, John, 1879-1880
  - Harris, Sadie, undated
  - Harrison, Benjamin, 1889
  - Hastings, Daniel H., 1898
  - Hay, John M., undated
  - Hepworth, J. G., 1892
  - Hertwig, J. G., 1869-1870
  - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1863-1870, undated
  - Holley, Sallie, 1867-1891, undated
  - Hollister, O. J., 1869
  - Hooker, Isabella Beecher, and family, 1864-1888, undated
  - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1907
  - Hull, Phoebe C., 1891-1894, undated
  - "H" miscellaneous, 1861-1906, undated (Box 9, Reel 11)
  - Irish, Elias H., 1864-1866, undated
  - Isom, S. May
    - 1892-1897
    - 1898, undated
  - "I" miscellaneous, 1865-1893, undated
  - Johnson, Oliver, 1864-1888
  - Jones, Melinda, 1872-1875, undated
  - "J" miscellaneous, 1863-1909, undated
  - Kelley, William D., 1863-1866, undated (Box 10, Reel 11)
  - "K" miscellaneous, 1863-1910, undated
  - Lamborn, Robert, 1866-1868
  - Lancaster, A. E., 1877-1879
  - Livermore, Mrs. D. P., 1863 (Box 10, Reel 12)
  - Locke, D. R., 1868-1880, undated
  - Logan, Olive, 1869-1871
  - "L" miscellaneous, 1863-1911, undated
  - McCullough, John, 1878-1879, undated
  - McDonald, Louisa and John E., 1891-1907
  - MacGeachy, Charles, 1891-1892, undated
  - MacKenzie, Addheid, 1877-1893, undated
  - McKim, James Miller, undated
  - May, Samuel (1810-1899), 1862-1863, undated
  - Meeker, Ralph, 1869-1879
  - Mendum, Charles A., 1881-1892, undated
  - Miles, Nellie E., 1871-1895, undated
  - Miller, Ann Jenness, 1893
  - "Ma" miscellaneous, 1861-1911, undated
  - "Mb-Mz" miscellaneous, 1863-1909, undated
  - Nicholas, [?], 1906-1909
  - Nunn, C. A., 1884-1891
  - "N" miscellaneous, 1863-1899
  - Osgood, James R., 1871-1874 (Box 11, Reel 13)
  - "O" miscellaneous, 1862-1910, undated
  - Palmer, A. M., 1875-1880
  - Perry, George, 1877-1885
  - Phillips, Wendell, 1863-1868, undated
  - Pomeroy, Samuel C. and Martha L., 1863-1873, undated
  - Prang, Louis, 1868-1893
  - Prescott, Benjamin F., 1862-1874
  - Price, Fanny Davenport and Edwin H., 1879-1881, undated
  - Pritchard, T. S., 1888
  - Pugh, T. B., 1864-1883
  - "P" miscellaneous, 1861-1907, undated
  - "Q" miscellaneous, 1892-1905, undated
  - Redpath, James, 1868-1879, undated (Box 11, Reel 14)
  - Reid, Whitelaw, 1863-1879, undated
  - Rich, Carol, 1879-1888, undated (Box 12, Reel 14)
  - Richardson, Leander P., 1874-1893, undated
  - Ricketson, Joseph, 1862-1863
  - Robinson, Aggie Day and Edith Day, 1908-1910, undated
  - Rogers, Stuart, 1887, undated
  - Runkle, L. G. and Cornelius A., 1870-1875, undated
  - "R" miscellaneous, 1862-1895, undated
  - Sanders, John, undated
  - Sargent, Christine K., 1864-1894
  - Schurz, Carl, 1871-1874, undated
  - Scovel, James M., 1869-1874
  - Seward, M., 1891
  - Shepard, Charles, 1873-1881
  - Smith, David R., 1891-1892
  - Smith, Nicholas, 1906-1907, undated
  - Spear, James Edwin, 1877-1881, undated
  - Spinner, Francis Elias, 1869-1870
  - Spofford, Harriet and R. S., 1865-1888, undated
  - Stanton, Elizabeth Cady, 1867-1868, undated
  - Stetson, John, 1881, undated
  - Stewart, Anna E., 1886-1887
  - Stone, Lucy, 1867-1881
  - Stowe, Harriet B., 1869, undated
  - Sullivan, Margaret, 1878-1880 (Box 12, Reel 15)
  - "Sa-Sk" miscellaneous, 1861-1911, undated
  - "Sl-Sz" miscellaneous, 1862-1910, undated
  - Tallman, E. P., 1886-1893 (Box 13, Reel 15)
  - Tarbell, Ida M., 1910
  - Tilton, Theodore, 1862-1872, undated
  - Tyler, Moses Coit, 1872
  - "T" miscellaneous, 1862-1910, undated
  - United States Senate, 1901-1902
  - "U" miscellaneous, 1865
  - "V" miscellaneous, 1884-1894, undated
  - Wakeman, Ann, 1878, undated
  - Warner, Charles Dudley, 1863-1874, undated
  - Warner, Susan, George, and Lillian, 1864-1881, undated
  - White, Charles, 1869-1871
  - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1871-1888
  - Whiting, Lilian, 1881-1895, undated
  - Whitlock, Brand, 1907-1908 (Box 13, Reel 16)
  - Wilder, Burt G., 1909-1910
  - Wilson, Henry, 1866-1874
  - Wood, Charles P. and Emma P., 1864-1874
  - Wood, S. N., 1867
  - Wright, Emily Dudley, 1887-1897, undated
  - "Wa-Wh" miscellaneous, 1863-1897, undated
  - "Wi-Wz" miscellaneous, 1863-1910, undated
  - "X-Z" miscellaneous, 1867-1883, undated
  - Anonymous, 1861-1877 (Box 14, Reel 16)
  - Calling card messages, 1870, undated
  - Fragments
    - By Dickinson, circa 1895-1905
    - By others, circa 1860-1900
  - Group letters, 1863-1882, undated
  - Unidentified
    - By "A.D.," 1887-1908, undated
    - By Anna Dickinson, 1862-1905, undated
  - First names
    - Julia, 1866-1884, undated
    - Louise, 1863-1875, undated
    - Other, 1867-1892, undated (Box 14, Reel 17)
  - Initialed letters, 1868-1910, undated
  - Unintelligible, 1859-1902, undated
- Speeches and Writings File, 1868-1907 (Box 15-21, Reel 17-21)
  Speeches, plays, and miscellaneous unidentified notes and manuscripts.
  Arranged by type of material and thereunder alphabetically by title.
  - Speeches (Box 15, Reel 17)
    - Andrew Johnson, undated
    - "A Threefold Tragedy," undated
    - Edward Parker, undated
    - Frederic Chopin, undated
    - Henrik Ibsen, undated
    - "Jeanne D'arc," 1884
    - Mormonism, undated
    - "National Crisis," undated
    - "Personal Liberty," undated
    - "Standard Bearers in the Teacher's Battle," undated
    - Temperance and Suffrage, 1868
    - "Whited Sepulchres," 1870
    - Women's Rights, undated
    - "Worth Fighting For," undated
    - Miscellaneous, undated
      - 1 of 3
      - 2 of 3
      - 3 of 3 (Box 15, Reel 18)
  - Plays (Box 16, Reel 18)
    - "A Crown of Thorns," 1876
      - Notebook
      - Act I
      - Act II
      - Act III
      - Act IV
      - Act I
      - Act II
      - Act III
      - Act IV
      - Musical score
      - Stage sketches
      - Miscellaneous
    - "An American Girl," 1880
      - Notes
      - Act I
      - Act II
      - Act III (Reel 18, Box 17)
      - Act IV
      - Act I-IV
      - Act I, annotated
      - Act II, annotated
      - Act III, annotated
      - Act IV, annotated
      - Roles of Cranford, Reirdon, and Stella
      - Role of Dr. Camp (Box 17, Reel 19)
      - Role of Fred
      - Role of Vivian
    - "Aurelian or Rome's Restorer," 1879
      - Act I
      - Act II
      - Act III
      - Act IV
      - Printed copy, annotated
      - Printed copy, annotated (Box 18, Reel 19)
    - "Esther Armin," 1879
    - "Laura," 1876
    - "The Test of Honor," 1880
      - Act I-II
      - Act III-IV
      - Bound copies, Acts I-II
      - Bound copies, Acts III-IV
    - Miscellaneous (Box 18, Reel 20)
      - Role of Claude Mulnotte, undated
      - Copyright, 1876-1907
  - Miscellany
    - Notes
      - 1 of 9
      - 2 of 9 (Box 19, Reel 20)
      - 3 of 9
      - 4 of 9
      - 5 of 9
      - 6 of 9
      - 7 of 9 (Box 19, Reel 21)
      - 8 of 9 (Box 20, Reel 21)
      - 9 of 9
    - Unidentified manuscripts
      - 1 of 5
      - 2 of 5
      - 3 of 5
      - 4 of 5
      - 5 of 5 (Box 21, Reel 21)
- Legal File, 1881-1898 (Box 21, Reel 22)
  Correspondence, court records, notebook of confinement, and miscellaneous legal documents.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic and chronologically thereunder.
  - Charge to the court, 1897 (Box 21, Reel 22)
  - Correspondence
    - Dailey, Bell & Crane, 1892-1896
    - Hart & Price, 1891
    - Heverin, James H., 1881-1891
    - Howe & Hummel, 1888-1896
    - McLean, William S., 1891-1896
    - Miscellaneous, 1895-1898
  - Court record, 1893
  - Notebook of confinement, 1893
  - Miscellaneous legal documents, 1888-1895
- Miscellany, 1863-1951 (Box 21-27, Reel 22-25)
  Address books, calling cards, financial papers, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, and other miscellaneous subject and printed matter concerning Dickinson, including research material compiled by Giraud Chester.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material. Research notes are located at the end of the series.
  - Address books, 1870-1872, undated (Box 21, Reel 22)
  - Calling cards, undated (Box 22, Reel 22)
    - 1 of 2
    - 2 of 2
  - Financial papers
    - Receipts
      - 1864-1881
      - 1882 (Box 22, Reel 23)
      - 1883-1930
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1875-1885
  - Newspaper clippings
    - Obituaries, 1932
    - Miscellaneous, undated
      - 1 of 14
      - 2 of 14
      - 3 of 14 (Box 23, Reel 23)
      - 4 of 14
      - 5 of 14
      - 6 of 14
      - 7 of 14
      - 8 of 14
      - 9 of 14
      - 10 of 14
      - 11 of 14
      - 12 of 14 (Box 24, Reel 23)
      - 13 of 14
      - 14 of 14
  - Passport, 1876 (Box 24, Reel 24)
  - Phrenological chart of Dickinson, 1866
  - Printed matter, undated
  - Programs and playbills, undated
  - Scrapbooks
    - circa 1877
    - circa 1877-1882 (Box 25, Reel 24)
    - circa 1879-1880
    - circa 1880-1881
    - circa 1888-1895 (Box 26, Reel 24)
    - circa 1891-1895 (Box 26, Reel 25)
    - circa 1907-1912
    - 1863-1876 See Oversize
    - circa 1876-1877 See Oversize
  - Research cards, compiled by Giraud Chester, 1950-1951, undated (Box 27, Reel 25)
- Addition, 1862-1933 (Box 28-29)
  Correspondence, photographs, engraving plates, printed matter, scrapbooks, and other papers.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Books, 1881, undated (Box 28)
  - Clippings, 1897-1933, undated
  - Correspondence, 1863, 1915, 1924, undated
  - Engraving plates for calling cards, envelopes, and related items, undated
    - 1 of 2
    - 2 of 2
  - Miscellany, 1864-1865, 1926
  - Notebook, 1920-1923
  - Photographs, undated
  - Printed matter, 1891, 1926, undated
  - Scrapbooks (Box 29)
    - 1891-1896
    - 1893-1896
    - 1897-1901
- Oversize, 1863-1877 (Box OV 1-OV 2, Reel 24-25)
  Oversize scrapbooks.
  Organized and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Miscellany (Box OV 1)
    - Scrapbooks
      - 1863-1876 (Container 26, reels 24-25)
      - circa 1876-1877 (Container 26, reels 24-25) (Box OV 2)